[Evans] There's one last type of memory in your computer that I want to talk about,
接下来我们还将讨论计算机中的另一种存储器
which is the hard drive.
也就是硬盘
This is what a hard drive looks like.
这就是一块硬盘
You can see that this hard drive has 1 terabyte of data.
可以看到 这块硬盘可以存储 1TB (百万兆字节) 的数据
If you turn it upside down, you can maybe get a little better sense of what's going on here.
如果把它翻过来 可以稍微清楚地看到其构造
It's a little hard to see.
这块硬盘看不大清楚
My wife drew the line at opening the hard drive,
我太太在这里划了条线
so I'm sorry I can't show you inside it.
不好意思 不能让大家看到硬盘的内部构造
But inside here there's a bunch of disks that are spinning,
在里面 有一些盘片在旋转
and the disks are storing data in a magnetic way,
盘片用磁性方式存储数据
and there's a read head that can read data from the disk
有磁头可以从盘片上读取数据
as well as write new data from the disk.
也可以将新数据写在盘片上
So this is a very slow way of storing data compared to what we have in the DRAM,
这种存储数据的方式相比 DRAM 来说慢很多
but it can store a lot more data with a lot less cost.
但是硬盘可以以更低廉的成本存储更多的数据
There are 2 important properties that the hard drive has.
硬盘有两个重要的属性
The hard drive is a lot bigger than the DRAM. It stores a lot more memory.
硬盘比 DRAM 大很多 可以存更多的数据
This was 2 gigabytes. This is 1 terabyte, so that's 500 times as much memory.
这个 DRAM 有2GB 这块硬盘则是1TB 是 DRAM 的500倍
And a terabyte is close to a trillion bytes, so that's 8 * 2 to the 40 bits,
1TB 大约是一万亿字节 也就是2的40次幂乘以8
which is equivalent to 8.8 trillion bits.
差不多是8.8万亿比特
This is enough memory to store about a quarter million songs.
这个容量可以存储25万首歌
The latency for a hard drive is much worse than the latency for the DRAM memory.
硬盘的延迟时间比 DRAM 长很多
And the reason for that, if you think about what you have to do
原因就在于
to get data out of the hard drive, you've got these disks that are spinning
要从硬盘中读取数据 这些盘片实实在在地旋转
in a physical thing, so you've got to wait until it spins to the point in the read head
我们需要耐心等待 等到磁头转到数据的位置
where you can read it.
来读取数据
If it's not in the right place, the read head also has to move across this.
如果磁头没有移到正确位置 就会继续寻找数据
You're moving real physical things, so that takes time.
所以磁头进行物理移动 这需要时间
The latency for a hard drive is about 7 milliseconds,
硬盘的延迟时间大约是7毫秒
and a millisecond is 1/1000th of a second.
1毫秒相当于1秒的千分之一
And that's the average time. The time varies depending on where the data is.
这是硬盘的平均延迟时间 根据数据位置不同会略有不同
So if you have to wait for it to spin all the way around and move to the head,
如果你要等盘片完整转一圈 磁头找到数据位置
that can take a lot longer.
花得时间可能更久
If you're lucky, the data is in the right place and it doesn't take that long.
如果运气好 数据就在附近 则不用很长时间
The cost of this hard drive is about $100 US dollars.
这块硬盘大约要100美元
So let's add the hard drive to our data table.
我们把硬盘也列入比较名单
For the quiz it's up to you to figure out the values for the hard drive in the data table.
你需要计算出硬盘的成本 这是测验内容
As a reminder, we said it was $100 US for a 1.0 terabyte hard drive.
提醒一下 1TB 硬盘的成本是100美元
Your goal is to figure out the number of bits.
你得到的答案单位应该是比特
I've told you the latency is 7 milliseconds. That's a milli, not a nano.
之前已经提到 硬盘的延迟时间是7毫秒 单位是毫秒 不是纳秒
You should be able to compute the latency distance.
有了这些数据 应该可以计算延迟距离了
The units to use for this are kilometers.
单位是千米